Shahin Nazarov

Experienced Senior Software Engineer with over six years working in cloud, financial, banking, betting, cryptographic, and e-commerce services companies involving extensive interaction and engagement with software design, documenting, testing, development, and monitoring. Currently seeking Software Engineering, Software Development, and Solution Architect positions and would be keen to learn and get comfortable with various tools and technologies if the requirements arise.



EXPERIENCES

G42 Cloud Technologies L.L.C., United Arab Emirates (UAE) — Senior Software Engineer

In progress

International Bank of Azerbaijan OJSC, Azerbaijan — Senior Software Engineer

JAN 2021 - MAY 2022

- Designing and developing a new **Loyalty Program**
- EDD implementation
- Planning and documenting technical specifications for features and system design
- Working closely with senior stakeholders to understand business requirements and help translate these to technical requirements for development team
- Writing testable, scalable and efficient codes and leading code reviews
- Directing development team in design, development, coding, testing and debugging of applications
- Mentoring junior team members and ensuring they adhere to determine software quality standards

Caspian Tech CJSC, Azerbaijan — Senior Software Engineer

MAY 2019 - JAN 2021

- Designing a new scalable **betting system**
- Making the standards for configurations, coding style, testing and documentation
- Applying zero-downtime deployment with Kubernetes technologies
- Making CD/CI infrastructure with versioning for all applications
- Creating and developing new applications both microservice and SOA based
- Implementing 3rd party odd providers (e.g. sportradar)
- Optimizing the betting system for passing provider's certification requirements

PERSONAL INFORMATION:

Phone: +994708900999

Email:

me@shahinnazarov.com

LinkedIn:shaheen-nazarov

Website:

shahinnazarov.com

GitHub: nazarov-pro

CERTIFICATIONS

CKAD: <u>Certified Kubernetes</u> <u>Application Developer</u>

OCP: Java SE 11 Developer

LANGUAGES

Azerbaijani (Native)

English (Professional)

• Developing risk management system with real-time data analyzing

PaySis LLC, Azerbaijan — Senior Software Engineer

JUNE 2018 - MAY 2019

- Making the payment system support multiple payment processors(e-comm)
- Implementing new integrations with aggregators and vendors
- Integrating with new payment processing systems (e.g. MasterPass)
- Optimizing the speed of the system using caching technologies
- Automating daily tasks for reporting
- Developing new projects and REST APIs for (mobile) clients

B.EST Solution LLC, Azerbaijan — Software Engineer

NOVEMBER 2017 - JUNE 2018

- Extending the open-source X-Road project by implementing new features
- Automating SOAP-based web services (generating STUB files and auto detecting new web services)
- Integrating e-signing services with Europe (OASIS DSS)
- Developing a management portal for signing/verifying
- Implementing CD/CI infrastructure and containerization all applications
- Optimizing the current system with implementing EDD patterns

CCI Technologies LLC, Azerbaijan — Software Developer

MAY 2016 - NOVEMBER 2017

- Developing new features for the ERP system
- Writing documentation for REST and SOAP web services
- Making UML diagrams(class, flow, use case, sequence)
- Applying new REST APIs in the client-side(web)
- Analyzing & optimizing SQL scripts
- Resolving bugs in website and backend with the feedback of the client

EDUCATION

Azerbaijan State University of Oil and Industry, Azerbaijan — *Master*

Information and Communication Technologies (ICT) Engineering

SEPTEMBER 2017 - JUNE 2019

Azerbaijan State University of Oil and Industry, Azerbaijan — Bachelor

Information and Communication Technologies (ICT) Engineering

SKILLS

Programming languages: Java (expert), Golang (proficient), Python (proficient)Software Architectural Design: Monolithic, Microservices, SOA, EDD, TDD, CQRS

API Protocols: REST, SOAP, GRPC

Application Frameworks: Spring [Core, Boot, Cloud, MVC, Data, Security],

Quarkus

SQL/ORM Frameworks: JPA, Hibernate, MyBatis, JOOQ

Databases (RDBMS/NoSQL): OracleDB, MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB,

Elasticsearch

DevOps Tools: Jenkins, GitLab Pipelines, Terraform[AWS, K8S], Docker, Kubernetes, Linux Shell Scripting, Nexus, ELK Stack, Graylog, Prometheus(with Grafana)

Cloud Technologies: AWS (EC2, S3, RDS, Lambda, ECS, ECR, EKS, CloudWatch...)

Other: Apache Kafka(Kafka Connect), RabbitMQ (with AMQP and MQTT

protocols), Maven, Gradle, Bazel, Redis, Memcached, Cryptography, WebSocket